starstable.com 2019-05-23

# Privacy policy | Star Stable

Star Stable is an online horse game for players all over the world where they can dive into the joys of riding and adventure. Star Stable Online is a product owned and developed by Star Stable Entertainment AB in Stockholm, Sweden.

This privacy policy applies to the online game and interactions contained in Star Stable Online available at [https://www.starstable.com](https://www.starstable.com/). The policy also applies to any services provided by Star Stable relating to the game: Star Stable website, mobile apps “services” and from different international variations. This privacy policy does not apply to third party companies or to sites which may link, or redirect, to Star Stable Entertainment AB sites or products. 

Our privacy policy may change from time to time. If we make any major changes to our policies, we will put a notice on our website or the application. If the change significantly affects registered users, we will send a notice to you by email. If we make any substantial changes in the way we handle children’s personal information, we will first notify and obtain the prior consent of a parent or legal guardian. 

Star Stable is compliant with the United States Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and a member of FTC approved PRIVO’s COPPA Safe Harbor Program. 

* ###  Our Privacy Policy 

Your personal data is valuable, and Star Stable appreciates that you rely on us to keep it safe. We constantly strive to earn the trust of our players and parents or legal guardians. So, although we’re required to change our data privacy policy to reflect global changes and EU legislation, we also want to take this opportunity to improve user experience. By updating our new policy, we hope that reading and navigating your way around is a more pleasant experience. We aim to do this by making communication simple and speaking in a clear, transparent voice. Our policy updates will make it easier for players and parents to have control over the data you entrust us with, so that we can provide you with a better game and a smarter way for you to manage your data on “My Account”. 

* ###  The data we collect 

We require users to register an account to play Star Stable Online. Star Stable will not collect from a child more personal data than is reasonably required to provide a technically stable and safe online game experience. 

By agreeing to the Terms and Conditions, or obtaining parent or legal guardian approval, Star Stable may possibly collect some of the following data: 

  * Player email address 
  * Parent email address where applicable 
  * Purchase data/history 
  * Customer I.D and data, such as name and age 
  * Account data 
  * IP address and log in details 

* ### What do we use the data for?

The reason Star Stable store player’s personal information is: 

  * So that we can create your unique account profile. 
  * To identify in which area you live, so that we know which laws and regulations apply to you. 
  * To identify the consent age in your area, so that we can help you to get parental/ legal guardian approval if needed. 
  * To make sure that you get the right version of the game for your country. 
  * So that you can get access to the site and game, in order to progress and get the best possible game experience. 
  * So that we can communicate with you about your account. 
  * So that we can send you news, if you have opted for this. 
  * For us to reach you regarding market offers, if you opted for it. 
  * For password maintenance. 

The reason we store personal data for you as a parent or legal guardian: 

  * To set up your payment method when you start a membership. 
  * To allow future payments processes. 
  * To maintain your consent history for privacy policy transparency, and guidelines on how Star Stable is allowed to use the player data. 
  * To store your billing address for future payments. 
  * To store your email address. 

Actual credit card or payment data is not stored by Star Stable Online but by our international-hosted payment providers. To be able to store information of this nature, we only use regulated providers who conform to the highest level of security. 

* ### How do we handle your data rights at Star Stable?

To follow the EU legislation as well as an increasing Global demand for enhanced data privacy we have updated our data handling processes and will continue delivering improved support to strengthen your personal rights to control how we at Star Stable handle your data. 

  1. ### CAN I CORRECT THE INFORMATION YOU HAVE ABOUT ME?

In case you would notice that we have the incorrect information about you, you can update and correct some information under “My Account”. If you find that you do not have the possibility to update the data you want please contact our Customer Support Team using our web-form. 

  2. ### CAN I WITHDRAW MY CONSENT AND RESTRICT DATA PROCESSING OF MY PERSONAL DATA?

If you decide that you no longer want to have an account with us you can always send a request to our Customer Support Team using our web-form. 

As a registered player you can update the consent for restricting us to contact you for Offers and Campaigns and/or contacting you for News and Information using “My Account”. 

We will handle most requests for consent removal, data update or removal or request for information within 30 days. In cases we need to verify your identification and ensure from a data integrity point of view that we are handling your account correctly, it may take up to 60 days. We will notify you if the process will take longer than 30 days. 

  3. ### CAN I REQUEST INFORMATION OR ASK FOR MY PERSONAL DATA TO BE REMOVED?

As a registered player you can request for your old email address to be removed. 

As a registered parent or legal guardian, you can request for any old email addresses to be deleted or payment methods to be removed. 

For safety purposes we securely store and archive old data. This is so it can be used to investigate any complaints or violations of our terms and conditions, or on the off-chance that it has been requested by law enforcement agencies or data protection authorities. 

Most of the data is fully available for you as a registered player under “My Account” or in the game. Please contact @Privacy (see section 11 below) if you have any additional requirements on obtaining more information about your persona data. 

  4. ### CAN I MOVE MY DATA FROM STAR STABLE?

Star Stable is under the EU GDPR law considered to be a Data Controller. As part of the law you should be able to move or port out your data to another Data Controller where so is applicable. For Star Stable this is only applicable to the private persons requesting the data since the products and services cannot be transferred to another Company. 

* ### Community or social features we offer and how we keep these areas safe.

Star Stable Online offers in-game chat and mail for our users. To keep our players safe, and actively prevent the exchange of personal information in line with COPPA and General Data Protection Regulation requirements, all in-game communications are filtered and behavior-profiled using technology provided by industry leader CRISP THINKING. All chat and mails are stored securely for investigation purposes should there be any cause for our trained team of moderators to thoroughly examine an interaction (such as a complaint, a violation of our terms of service, or a request for information from a law enforcement agency). 

This is currently the only automated decision making at Star Stable. 

* ###  Cookies and web technology 

####  Cookies 

Star Stable Online uses so-called cookies on the website in order to provide the user access to certain functions and to obtain information regarding visits to the website. 

####  What are cookies? 

A cookie is a small text file which is stored on the user's computer and which contains information. There are two types of cookies. One type of cookie is a ’permanent’ cookie which saves a file permanently on the user's computer until the file is removed. The other type of cookie is called a session cookie which disappears when the user closes his or her web browser. 

Session cookies are sent between the user's computer and Star Stable Online's servers in order to keep track of information regarding the user, for example, which user name is used. 

To make it easier for our players, Star Stable uses permanent cookies, which can provide the user with access to stored information, such as how to use our services. 

The information collected via cookies may be linked to personal information we’ve collected about you. 

Anonymized information from permanent cookies is also used for maintaining statistics, regarding the use of the website, to conduct surveys in order to improve the service, or to determine which parts of our services are most popular, so we can make it as user-friendly as possible. 

####  Star Stable Online also uses the following third-party cookies: 

Google Analytics - cookies are used to collect information regarding the way the user uses the website, e.g. which parts the user visits most frequently. This is so that we can in analyze how the website is used and improve user experience. More information is available at: [https://developers.google.com](https://developers.google.com/)

Star Stable may allow third parties to place and read their own cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect information through the Services. The reasons are to allow our third-party service providers to collect information that helps us with traffic measurement, research, and analytics. 

####  How can the user remove cookies? 

The user can choose whether he or she wishes to accept cookies. By adjusting the web browser, the user may avoid receiving cookies. However, this could cause failure in the function of the service. The method used to block cookies will depend on the web browser used. Consult the "Help" or corresponding menu in the web browser for instructions. 

* ###  Do we have e-commerce or advertisements on our site? 

Star Stable Online does not advertise any third-party products or services. To allow us to operate as an advertising-free business, our website Star Stable Online sells membership time (subscription) and in-game currency (Star Coins) that can be used to purchase in-game items. 

* ###  What is a Star Stable membership? 

We want everyone to have the opportunity to play Star Stable Online. That’s why we have a free area of the game that can be played indefinitely. For those wishing to get into the game in more depth, there is a Star Stable world reserved for subscription members (or Star Riders as they are called in Star Stable). Star Stable subscription is a paid service, with different subscription packages according to your level of commitment. 

Our purchase packages range from recurring 1 month or 3 months Star Rider subscriptions or the 'pay once' Star Rider option that gives you access to the member area of Star Stable. Prices of these memberships vary by national region and currency. Star Stable memberships can be cancelled at any time on your “My Account” pages or by contacting customer support through our web contact form. 

Purchases must be approved by the cardholder or the payment method account holder. Should a payment method be used without permission, please contact us via our support form as soon as possible. 

* ###  With whom do we share your information? 

Personal information is not shared with independent third parties for their own marketing purposes. To operate the service, we may make personal and anonymous information available to third parties in these limited circumstances: (1) with vendors who help us operate our website or online service, such as payment processors, (2) with your express consent (or the prior consent of a parent or legal guardian), (3) when we believe it to be required by law, (4) when we believe that it is necessary to protect our rights or property, or (5) to any successor or purchaser in a merger, acquisition, liquidation, dissolution or sale of assets, provided they adhere to the same practices in this policy. 

* ###  How do we keep your information secure? 

At Star Stable we respect the information you entrust to us and take pride in protecting it from unauthorized access or disclosure. Therefore, we have updated both administrative routines, work constantly with training our staff in data privacy protection, and are constantly updating and improving our electronic solutions to keep your data safe. This includes utilizing Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts all the personal information you give us, and storing your information behind a firewall designed to block access from outside our network. However, although we always do our utmost to protect your data, no security or encryption method can be completely guaranteed to protect information from hackers or human error. 

Information we collect may be stored or processed on computers located in any country where we do business. 

* ###  How do we comply with privacy regulations for children 12   
and under in the United States? 

Children and their parents in the US have the same rights as our users in the EU which are outlined in this privacy policy. Parents must provide consent for their child to use Star Stable. Please refer to section [2](https://www.starstable.com/en/privacy#b) and [3](https://www.starstable.com/en/privacy#c) to find out what personal information we collect and how we use it. 

Star Stable (owned and operated by Star Stable Entertainment AB) is included in PRIVO’s Kids Privacy Assured COPPA Safe Harbor Certification Program (“the Program”). The Program certification applies to the digital properties listed on the validation page that is viewable by clicking on the PRIVO seal. PRIVO is an independent, third-party organization committed to safeguarding children's personal information collected online. PRIVO aims to help parents and their children exercise control over personal information while exploring the Internet. The PRIVO COPPA certification seal posted on this page indicates Star Stable has established COPPA compliant privacy practices and has agreed to submit to PRIVO’s oversight and consumer dispute resolution process. If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact us using the category Privacy on our [web-form](https://www.starstable.com/en/support). If you have further concerns after you have contacted us, you can contact PRIVO directly at [[email protected]](https://www.starstable.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4434362d3225273d0434362d322b6a272b29)

#### Kids Privacy Assured by PRIVO: COPPA Safe Harbor Certification & GDPRkids™

#### GDPRkids™ Privacy Assured

The Program applies to the digital properties listed on the validation page that is viewable by clicking on the PRIVO GDPRkids™ Verified Shield. The PRIVO GDPRkids™ Privacy Assured Program supports child directed services known as Information Society Services under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), to comply with the requirements of this legislation. It impacts any child directed service in an EU Member State and any service globally that collects and or processes the personal data of children and minors. There is no safe harbor for the GDPR to date, but to ensure this company's services meet the program requirements, we conduct regular monitoring and consulting. 

THIRD PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS

We use the following third-party service providers in relation to users 12 and under in the U.S. These third-party services do not share your information with any other third parties. Please contact Star Stable at [web-form](https://www.starstable.com/en/support) for more information on their collection and use practices. 

  * Google Analytics in our apps
  * Google Ad services
  * Zendesk for customer service
  * Crisp Thinking for chat moderation

* ### How can you Contact us with Privacy Questions or Concerns?

We are happy to answer any questions you might have concerning your personal Data, third-party processors or in-game safety. For general questions, please contact our Customer Support Team using our [web-form](https://www.starstable.com/en/support). 

Should you have specific Data Privacy and Internet Safety questions and/or concerns or want to have information about your private data or reach our Data Protection Officer (DPO), please use our category Privacy on our [web-form](https://www.starstable.com/en/support). Should you not find any good choice for your questions, please email at [[email protected]](https://www.starstable.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#cdbdbfa4bbacaeb48dbeb9acbfbeb9acafa1a8e3aea2a0) or call at +46 10 3300106. 

If you have further compliance questions regarding EU law and GDPR please use this link to find the relevant contact details for the Data Protection Authority in your country:  
[ http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080 ](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080)

Or reach us at our corporate headquarters at: 

Star Stable Entertainment AB  
Att: Privacy Request / Customer Care  
Vasagatan 16  
111 20 Stockholm  
SWEDEN  

Privacy Policy Version 1.2.1
